

# **Summary**

Data scientist and machine learning researcher with over 10 years of combined experience in industry R&D and academic research environments. With a computer science and computer engineering background, I have a comprehensive understanding and knowledge of the machine learning applications development life cycle, from data acquisition, storage, reproducible deployment and evaluation, as well as a publication track record in these topics. I have developed methodologies for objective time series evaluation as well as subsequent time series synthesis using Generative Adversarial Networks. My core strengths lie in methodological problem assessment and solution and a goal-oriented approach. I am seeking Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer opportunities where I apply my know-how and deliver high quality data analysis insights and results.

# **Experience**

**Ulm University**Ulm, Germany

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE, LECTURER

Jan. 2018 - Dec. 2023

- STEALTH Project (2020-2022):
  - STEALTH: Anonymisation through Privacy-preserving Data Generation
  - Senior researcher, synthetic time series generation.
- Al Investments Project (2019-2021):
  - All: An advanced investment tool based on machine learning and big data.
  - Data scientist & scientific consultant for time series analysis and generation.
- RECAP Project (2018-2019):
  - RECAP: Reliable Capacity Provisioning and Enhanced Remediation for Distributed Cloud Applications
  - Data science tasks & research on time series generation for cloud and telecommunication data (Partnership with Britsh Telecom).
  - Assistance in project and deliverables coordination.

#### Daimler AG, Mercedes Benz Research and Development (MBRD)

Ulm, Sindelfingen, Germany

Working Student, Intern, Bachelor- & Masterthesis

Juli. 2011 - Apr. 2017

- · Research- and series development of several camera monitor prototype vehicles (replacement of the side-mirror with a camera and display)
- Research on surround vision systems (360 degree cameras)
- Night vision near infrared image colorization using synthetic images research

S.A.D. GmbH Ulm, Germany

STUDENT SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mai. 2010 - Mai. 2011

- Development of dashboards for tracking and predicting downloads of S.A.D. software
- Development of business relations in Ukrainian market

# **Education**

Ulm University Ulm, Germany

Ph.D. COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2023

• Submission: January 2024

• Ph.D. thesis topic: Synthetic Time Series Workload Generation

Ulm University Ulm, Germany

M.Sc. Computer Science

Mar. 2014 - Aug. 2017

• GPA 1.3 (very good), Majors: Computer Vision, Distributed Systems

• Master thesis topic: Luminance Estimation of Colorized Near-Infrared Images (research performed at MBRD UIm) Grade: 1.0

#### **Ulm University of Applied Sciences**

Ulm, Germany

B.Sc. Computer Engineering

Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2014

- GPA 1.4 (very good)
- Bachelor thesis topic: Low-light Image Quality Optimization of HDR Cameras (research performed at MBRD Sindelfingen) Grade: 1.3

### Skills\_

**Data-Driven** Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Analysis, Visualization, Computer Vision, Reproducible Research

**Technologies** Scikit, Pandas, Keras, JupyterLab, Kubernetes, TimeScale DB, InfluxDB

**Programming** MATLAB, Python, SQL, JAVA, C++, C#

Languages German (fluent), English (fluent), Russian (fluent), Hebrew (basic knowledge)

## Other\_

**FUNDING**Ulm University

VECTOR STIFTUNG STEM RESEARCH GRANT (€120.000)

- Project STEALTH:
- · Anonymisation through Privacy-preserving Data Generation

TEACHING ACTIVITIES Ulm University

LECTURER, SUPERVISOR

Jan. 2018 - PRESENT

Jan. 2020 - Oct. 2022

- Supervision of 3 M.Sc. Thesis & 4 B.Sc. Thesis
- Lecture Exercise Introduction to Deep Learning
- Seminar in Selected Topics in Machine Learning (over 15 student works supervised)

## **Selected Publications**

#### Optimization of demanding scenarios in CMS and image quality criteria

LEZNIK & TERZIS, HANDBOOK OF CAMERA MONITOR SYSTEMS:

2016

THE AUTOMOTIVE MIRROR-REPLACEMENT TECHNOLOGY BASED ON ISO 16505

2010

#### Multivariate time series synthesis using generative adversarial networks

LEZNIK ET AL., INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PERFORMANCE ENGINEERING ICPE 2021, ACM/SPEC

2021

# The Great GAN Bake Off, An Extensive Systematic Evaluation of Generative Adversarial Network Architectures for Time Series Synthesis

LEZNIK ET AL., JSYS, JOURNAL OF SYSTEMS RESEARCH

2022

## **Academic Service & Committees**

2021- **Vice-Chair**, SPEC Research Group, RG Predictive Data Analytics Working Group Gainesville, USA

Organization Committee, The Second International Workshop on Performance - Data Analytics and
Data-Management

Coimbra, Portugal

Organization Committee, The First International Workshop on Performance - Data Analytics and Data-Management

Beijing, China

## **References**

#### Dr. Christoph Rößing, Mercedes-Benz AG, Sindelfingen, Germany

TEAM LEAD AUTOMATED DRIVING COOPERATION NVIDIA christoph.roessing@mercedes-benz.com

#### Prof. Paolo Casari, University of Trento, Italy

Associate Professor, Dep. of Information Eng. and Computer Science paolo.casari@unitn.it

#### Dr. André Bauer, University of Chicago, USA

Postdoctoral Researcher, Globus Lab, Dep. Computer Science andrebauer@uchicago.edu